

arturgrygorian3@gmail.com

https://medium.com/@arturgrugorian3 https://github.com/ArturGR3

SUMMARY

With a decade of hands-on experience spanning supply chain and eCommerce, I bring a wealth of knowledge in advanced data analytics, modeling, and team leadership. In my new role I am looking to solve complex analytical problems using modern machine learning and Al tools.

EDUCATION

Master's in Statistics

Georgia Southern University Statesboro, GA, USA 2015 -2017

Master's in Economics

Kyiv School of Economics Kyiv, Ukraine 2012 - 2014

Master's in Mathematics

Odesa National University Odesa, Ukraine 2007 - 2013

TECHNOLOGY STACK

- Python, R
- SQL (BigQuery, SQL Server)
- Data Visualization (Tableau, Data Studio)
- Machine learning (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, AutoGluon)
- MLOPs (Docker, MLflow)
- GenAl (Instructor, RAG, LangChain)

ARTUR GRYGORIAN

Data Science @ Analytics Leader



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Manager Analytics (Global Fulfilment Speed) Wayfair, Berlin, Germany

Aug 2022 – Aug 2024

- Head of Global (EU, UK, USA) analytics responsible for strategy and tech implementation to improve delivery promise accuracy
- Boosted speed badging (fast delivery promise saturation) by 1500 bps by improving accuracy of delivery speed model and resolving tech debt
- Collaborated with ML engineers to design and implement A/B testing, measuring the conversion impact of faster delivery promise to justify strategic initiatives

Analytics Manager (EU Fulfilment Speed) Wayfair, Berlin, Germany

Jun 2021 – Aug 2022

- Led EU efforts to improve delivery promise accuracy, with a specific focus on supplier lead time and carrier speed
- Developed a delivery time estimation model for the EU network that improved speed by 1.3 days, resulting in a substantial increase in conversion that brought an additional ~€10M in annual GRS
- Established key performance indicators (KPIs) and designed supportive dashboards to evaluate the health of the delivery network. Led Weekly Business Reviews (WBRs) and Monthly Business Reviews (MBRs), bringing insights to executive leadership

Analytics Manager (Delivery Speed) The Home Depot, Atlanta, GA, USA

Sep 2019 - Apr 2021

- Created an ML model that improved delivery promise by 0.7 days without impact on reliability, resulting in ~\$100M in annual GRS via higher conversion
- Supported operations teams with data insights, uncovered problematic areas in the network through exploratory analytics, and collaborated on solutions
- Established and led data science team from inception, hiring, mentoring, and guiding the team to become one of the most impactful teams in the Delivery organization

Senior Data Analyst (Inbound Network Optimization) The Home Depot, Atlanta, GA, USA

Aug 2017 - Sep 2019

- Developed and implemented a truckload rounding model, resulting in annual savings of ~\$5M in transportation costs
- Implemented enhancements to the truckload planning model, including the migration of the legacy model from SQL Server to Google BigQuery
- Created multiple dashboards to monitor key performance indicators (KPIs) and shared insights during Weekly Business Reviews (WBRs) with the team
- Recognized for outstanding performance, promoted to Senior Data Analyst in 10 months